Erry Kostala

I am a senior developer with 6 years of experience. I am skilled in designing reliable and performant systems, integrating with third parties, and building solutions from the ground up. In my next role, I am looking to take technical leadership of a project and bring it to completion.

London E14
https://www.errietta.me

https://www.errietta.me/ errietta@errietta.me

EXPERIENCE

Lantum LTD, London — Senior Software Engineer

July 2019 - PRESENT

- API Design and Development

As a **technical lead**, led the architectural design and development of a new Microservice API for timesheet submission and auditing for freelance Locum staff working for NHS practices.

- Integration

As a **technical lead**, led a project to integrate the Lantum platform with the NHS Electronic Staff Record, including management of payroll, annual leave, and education for staff.

Devops

Led the deployment of a new kubernetes cluster to aid the launch of our new US-based product. Took the initiative to set up AWS X-Ray to audit and improve service performance. Led an effort to improve the performance of slower API routes.

Skills: Microservices, Python, Devops, AWS, PostgreSQL, Software Performance

Zoopla LTD, London — Software Engineer

August 2018 - July 2019

High Performance Software Engineering

As part of an award-winning team (women in tech engineering product team of the year), led the design and development of a new Python & Elasticsearch based API for searching new build developments serving thousands of users on Zoopla.

Devops

Led the creation of terraform templates for new ECS instances, which were deployed with Jenkins.

- Mentoring

Took initiative in mentoring a Junior Developer in JavaScript development and good practices.

Skills: Python, Node.js, Devops, AWS, MySQL

SKILLS

- Python
- Node.JS
- AWS
- Typescript
- PostgreSQL & MySQL
- NoSQL (MongoDB)
- Microservices
- Functional Programming
- Test-Driven Development

Interests

- Mentoring
- Moving fast & doing things right
- Modern technologies
- Microservices
- Software performance

FairFX PLC, London — Software Architect

May 2016 - August 2018

Database Design

Led the re-design of a database schema to meet new requirements in functionality.

Integration/API design

Co-led a project to integrate the FairFX API with a third-party card processor, which involved a refactor of a large part of the codebase.

Web Security

Led an effort in finding and resolving security issues such as Cross-Site scripting and SQL injection, as well as keeping the platform PCI compliant.

Skills: Perl, Node.js, Typescript, AWS, PostgreSQL

Self-Employed — Freelance Software Developer

2013 - May 2016

Mobile application development

Developed an e-learning mobile video player for a client.

Web development

PHP & Javascript web development for various clients.

Skills: Node.js, MongoDB, Angular.js, ionic.js, PHP, Javascript

Shadowcat Systems, Lancaster — *Software Developer*

July 2015 - July 2016

Payment processing

Led the paypal integration for a SaaS platform for a client.

- E2E testing

Led the black-box testing of a client API and wrote documentation for the API.

Skills: Perl, JavaScript, Client communication

Talks

- Building APIs with Node.js, Lambda & Serverless London Jan 2019 https://erk.sh/lnug1901
- Introduction to modern Javascript London June 2018 https://erk.sh/es6
- Perl dependency management London Oct 2017 https://erk.sh/perl-deps

Education

University of Huddersfield, Huddersfield— *BSc. Web Technologies*

First class